Never forget why you are the church.
Well, if you're happy, Lord, say amen.
It's been a while since I, uh, did both things at once,
so we are we are here.
Aren't you glad it's Jesus only Jesus?
We don't have to depend on anything or anyone else, just him.
And he is dependable and faithful.
Amen.
Turn your Bibles to Romans chapter 12.
Romans chapter 12.
I'll turn there with you.
Did anyone know those songs?
Then remember how we used to sing those songs all the time?
Okay, all right.
Some fun ones.
First one, 1st time I heard, Jesus only Jesus was at a men's
conference, and it was Charles Billingsley that sang it, and
it was, I looked down and then my feet were fluttering.
You know what I'm saying?
It was like, whoa, what is this?
It was absolutely phenomenal and I loved it every ever since.
But we're back in Romans chapter 12.
And in the church,
how we conduct our relationships with each other, is
one of the greatest witnesses for Christ to the world.
Now, remember, we're talking about, you know, we're talking about the
impact of the gospel in our relationships,
and it can either draw people in.
or push people away.
So God's word we learned last week, we're going to dive right into it,
has several commands on how we are to relate to each other.
Let's read the text this morning, then we're going to continue to break it down.
If you're in Romans chapter 12, starting in verse 10, say, read.
Be kindly affection one to another.
With brotherly love.
In honor preferring one another, not slothful
in business, fervent in spirit, serving the Lord.
Rejoicing in hope, patient in tribulation,
continuing instant in prayer, distributing to the necessity
of saints given to hospitality.
Now, last week, we took a deep look at Romans chapter
12, verse 10, it says, be kindly affection, one
to another, where brotherly love and honor preferring one another.
I like the phrasing of the NASB 95.
It says, just be devoted to one another in brotherly love.
Give preference to one another in honor.
See, our devotion to one another is a
critical part of the ministry of Cedar Grove
and every other New Testament local church.
A church family cannot be effective with a
take them or leave them mentality.
We had to be devoted to each other.
As a matter of fact, I told you last week, there was 2 phone
calls that were on my heart to make, right after preaching this, being devoted.
And I made those phone calls.
And I didn't get to talk to them until later because they didn't answer because,
you know, when the preacher calls you when you ain't at church after Sunday
service, you typically ignore those phone calls.
Amen?
But so I called them and we got to talk, but it was simple.
And I confess to them very simply.
I said, listen, sometimes in my assumption,
and in my in my pride and in my fear,
as long as I don't call, then it's just assumption.
Does that mean, are y'all with me?
But see, understand, sometimes and most of
the time that I've found is that when you call problems can be resolved.
And so we have to be devoted, one to
another, in brotherly love, affection enough to
make that phone call, to send that text,
to go across the church even, maybe, and sit
down with somebody and talk with them and love on them and
encourage them and pray with them.
I can tell you that, you know, I know Cedar Grove.
We have a family feel, and most people that come here, the 1st thing
they say is, man, I felt so welcomed and I felt so so apart.
Can I tell you something?
That should never change just because they become a member.
I want to clarify something here.
If you are constantly in the middle of strife and conflict within the church
family, and it is not limited to one particular situation
or person, but rather it is a pattern.
The common denominator is not the church, it is you.
There's too many people walking around with church hurt.
Me and Brother Law was talking about this.
I forget exactly what it was.
He was like, man, I don't, I know what church hurt is, and I understand what you're saying.
He said, but I just, I don't believe in it like that.
And you know what?
I'm telling you right now.
We're not saying that the church can't hurt you.
Someone by acting out of line with scripture, a poor leadership,
that stuff can happen.
However, to live your life with the constant excuse of past
churchyard and not being able to trust anyone is not
on the bride of Christ, that's on you.
When people sit there, my tie is going all over the place right now.
Y'all seeing that?
That's embarrassing.
When my goodness gracious.
When people tell me, well, I don't go to church, why?
Well, I just I had a bad experience.
Well, me too.
I've had a bad experience.
But you know who I, you know who I love more than that bad experience?
Jesus.
You know who Jesus loves?
The church.
I've been hurt.
Trust me, when you realize what it is important and what is not, when you understand the purpose,
we have of magnifying the name of Christ, when you acknowledge your own faults
and sin, church hurt becomes quite a silly way to live.
Again, I'm not saying that bad things don't happen.
I'm not saying that we are overlooking your pain.
What I'm trying to say is we got to get through it together.
How can he prevents this tragedy in the church?
Well, follow God's commands.
Almost 1210, be devoted to one another and brother love.
Give preference to one another in honor.
I guarantee you that would stop a lot of the conflict.
If we started trying to outdo each other and showing honor and
respect and worth and value, that would do away with
a lot of the problems that we have in the local church.
And see, here's the thing.
There won't be time for all the baggage and gripes, just godly affection and love.
Remember, we must be devoted.
All right?
But this morning, we move along to the next command.
Whereas being devoted to one another shows our love and affection
for each other, the next command speaks on, the believer's attitude.
The believer's attitude.
Let's pray, Father, I thank you for your word.
I thank you for an attentive ear.
This morning, God.
I thank you, Lord, for those that are here, God, for those that were not able to be here,
God, I pray, God, they are able to come back soon.
We pray for the kids that are being taught the gospel this morning, all the way to the babies.
Lord, we thank you.
We thank you for those that are serving to make something like this possible.
God, just have those to have ears to hear, may they hear.
In Jesus name, pray.
And everybody said?
Amen.
Now, what's an attitude?
Well, the definition of an attitude is a settled way of thinking, feeling,
or behaving that reflects a person's disposition or outlook.
That's what an attitude is.
Notice that 1st part right there.
And I think it is kind of telling a attitude is a settled way of thinking.
In other words, you don't have any intention of thinking
any other way than what you think right now.
That's an attitude.
Scripture tells us that what is in the heart comes out the mouth.
In other words, how you act and talk and think shows who
and what you truly are.
Before Christ, our attitude is carnal and egosentric.
We were children of disobedience, given to the lust
of the flesh.
We had a settled way of thinking.
We had a settled way of feeling.
We had a settled way of behaving because our father was not God,
but the devil, and it was reflected in our disposition and outlook on life.
That's who we once was.
If you're born again, though, that can't be who you still are.
When we become born again, everything changes.
What is a significant part of our spiritual transformation?
Well, if you remember the beginning of Romans 12 when we started this chapter
4 months ago, look at verse one.
Therefore, I urge you, brethren, by the mercies of God to
present your bodies, a living and holy sacrifice, acceptable
to God, which is your spiritual service of worship?
And do not be conformed to this world.
How, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind
so that you may prove what the will of God is
and which is good and acceptable and perfect.
In other words, you have to have an attitude adjustment.
Can I just be open this morning?
We've got too many professing Christians with the stinkiest, sourist,
room deflating poor attitudes.
Can I tell you something, if people get quiet when you walk in a room,
It ain't the people in the room.
It's your attitude.
When you walk into church and someone says, oh, man.
What is gonna happen today?
That's not, that's not, that's your attitude.
When you walk, men, when you walk in at home and
you start to just, your wife immediately shuts
down or goes to the, goes to wherever she goes and tries to avoid you.
listen, that's not her fault.
That's your bad attitude's fault.
Well, that's just how God made me.
No, it isn't.
If God has made you new, it isn't.
Show me in scripture where it says or insinuates or
even gives principle to justifying a bad attitude.
You can't find it.
You won't find it.
But so often we allow the noise and discomfort externally to
make us simply terrible to be around.
And I told you, this is going to be a hard one, did I not?
I warned you
I have watched some of the sweetest of members go from kind-hearted
to complete peace records the moment something doesn't go their way.
Listen, don't be don't don't be deceived.
That kindness and that sweet, that sweetness, that's not who they really are.
You do something they don't like.
That's who they really are.
We minister in a culture that we are kind harder to those who
invest in us spiritually, until they say or do something we don't
like, then all of a sudden it's eye roll city.
Anyone got any kids?
You like when they roll their eyes at you?
It looks uglier as an adult.
Don't even get me started about the culture of parenting we have in this world.
Listen, I have her see it for you.
And I wasn't able to say this all the time.
I remember when I 1st started, when River, we announced that,
and I remember how I said, I said, everyone get your counters out, we got a big event coming.
I think it was going to be March 7th.
Man, I still remember this.
like vividly.
And everyone's sitting here and I said, okay, put it down.
We're having a baby and everyone, everyone just, and it was such a
weight off my back because it was like, man, now I can be a dad and
people can't say, I don't know.
And I still don't know, amen.
But listen, I have a secret for you.
None of us who wouldn't know how to parent.
Our parents didn't really know how what they were doing.
That's why you're messed up.
Their parents, their parents didn't know really what they were doing.
That's why they're messed up.
Are y'all with me?
But guess what?
The rules apply it to you and your kid, just like they apply to everyone else.
We've got to stop this I know better attitude.
It stinks and the world smells it from a mile.
away.
By the way, you know, we sit here and we talk about our children's,
we have volunteers here and now we have volunteers.
They spend hours and hours ministering
to your children, not their own children, but your children.
And there's people that have the audacity.
to try to question or attack a volunteer
in the church when you got a dusty Bible by your kid's bedside.
Hello?
That's a bad attitude.
I am thankful.
for the men and women that have poured into my kids.
And guess what?
They have bad days too.
They may not do everything that I, listen, everyone, everyone wants everyone
wants the certain person to do this, do that.
Let me just tell you something.
I can tell you this.
They're teaching your kids the word.
can work from there.
Are y'all with me this morning, man?
You've got to stop this.
I know better.
It stinks.
Now, what does this attitude check look like?
As a matter of fact, I like that.
So this is what we're going to look.
We going to look at it.
We going to call it a biblical attitude check.
We're going to look at the next few verses, and we're going to look at what
it looks like to have a biblical attitude check.
So as a born again believer, eternally impacted by
the gospel of Jesus Christ.
We must be diligent, the Bible says.
Look at Romans 12, verse 11.
It says not slothful in business.
The NSB 95 says it like this, not lagging behind in diligence.
This speaks on this speaks on one's zeal in
what they are doing for the Lord.
In other words, God commands us to not be lazy.
There are many warnings against laziness in scripture.
Let me just give you several here.
Proverbs 1915.
Laziness cast into a deep sleep, and an
idle man will suffer hunger.
Proverbs 20 verse 4.
The slugger does not plow after the autumn, so he begs during the
harvest and has nothing.
Proverbs 26, 14, and 15 as the door turns
on its hinges, so does the sluggard on his bed.
The sluggard buries his hand in a dish and he is weary
of bringing it to his mouth again.
Ecclesiastes 10, 18, because of laziness,
the building decays and through idleness of hands, the
house leaks.
Paul wrote to the believers in Thessalonica about working
and we all love to quote it.
Thessalonians 3.10 for even when we were with you, we
used to give you this order.
If anyone is not willing to work, then he is not
to eat either.
Church, one of the worst ways to point people to Christ is
to live a lazy life.
We live in a culture that believes they deserve now what only years of hard work can give them.
They get into an industry and they work for a year or don't work
or just they're around and they clock in and say, okay, it's my time to own the place now.
That's the entitlement that we have in
the world and culture that we live in.
The statistics are alarming.
Multiple studies on teenage employment shows a sharp decrease in
the rate of teenage workers.
Some cite a number of around 70% of teenagers,
16 through 19 do not work a job at all.
And you say, well, what are you, what are you to talk?
Man, when I was 16 years old, am I getting old enough to say this?
Back in the day, I'm going to scare you with the year.
Back in like 2012.
Y'all be like, oh.
Anyway, So I shouldn't even said that.
But either way, listen, my 1st job was drywall carts.
Anyone on the drywall card is?
I still don't know what a drywall card is, but I made them.
And I was notching steel.
I was, I was,
I mean, it was like a warehouse job.
I'm talking like it was insane.
And man, it was, it was,
I mean, we were painting, we were doing this, we were doing that.
And it was right up the road.
I didn't even drive to work.
I rode my bike to work, and man, I worked like a stinking dog.
And I remember I thought I was, I thought I was wealthy.
It was like $8 an hour.
And man, I'm thinking like, uh-huh, here I come.
Amen.
I'm about to buy me a house.
I'm about to buy me a yacht.
Like I was like, I am rich now.
But listen, hey, I didn't I didn't always like it.
But you know what?
Work is good.
Work is something that God commands.
The 1st person that God created.
God gave him a job to do.
Historically, summertime has been a steady increase in teenage workforce
yet patterns show less teenagers are working in the summer as well.
Well, it's a teenager, you know, they ought to enjoy their freedom.
You're only a teenager once.
Well, amen.
I agree with that.
But let's not forget that this attitude towards work is entering
adulthood as well.
We're raising laziness and they're going into adulthood,
grown-ups as lazy.
According to bipartisan policy center, 20% of prime aged
adults are not in the workforce.
So even looking for employment.
This is adults ranging 25 to 54 years old.
For the reasons range from disability, illness, all the way to full-time
school or travel in the world, to being focused on recreation.
Now, listen, this ability is for some is a real thing.
However, let me explain in one word our nation's problematic
relation with working, laziness.
Now, before you before I get any kind of
domestic engineers coming to my office at the church.
I believe keeping a home, and I believe tending
to the kids, I believe that's work.
That's what my wife is doing right now, right as we speak, right as
I'm doing my work, she's doing work as well.
So don't ever think I'm looking down upon that.
But we got to be doing something.
Well, preacher, you know, I know people say, well, you got it easy.
You got a schedule and this and that.
I do remember, again, I'm making myself feel old.
I do remember going years going to school, working 2
part-time jobs preaching 3 times a week at a minimum,
doing that as a newlywed, being up here until 12
to one o'clock in the morning, trying to figure out what I was going to feed the
people because I didn't have no idea.
Listen, there's sometimes you just have to just work.
And I believe God blessed it.
God commands the believer to not be lazy, but rather be zealous in their work.
Zeal is the opposite of lazy.
Z creates diligence.
Zeal creates urgency.
Someone who is zealous is someone who desires to do a
good job, no matter the cost.
Titus 214 explains a believer's attitude on working, for
the grace of God has appeared, bringing salvation to all men,
instructing us to deny ungodliness, and worldly desires,
and to live sensibly, righteously and godly in the present
age, looking for the blessed hope and the appearing of the glory
of our great God and Savior, Christ Jesus, who gave himself
for us, to redeem us, from every lawless deed, and
to purify for himself, a people for his own possession.
Look what it says.
zealous for good deeds.
How diligent are you at work?
Are you known as the griper all day?
There, but useless.
Listen, I can't tell you how many times we've had church projects at
the church and listen, I don't know how to do much.
As a matter of fact, this morning, you've pretty much seen every skill I have in life.
You know what I'm saying?
That's about it.
But I remember Richard dealing so many times we'd have work projects
and I come, I come and I used to dress up throughout
the week and stuff, you know?
And because, you know, that's what pastors was supposed to do.
And he said, what up, blister?
I'd be like, what do you mean?
What does that mean?
He said, well, the work's done and you're just now showing up.
Listen, can I tell you something?
We've got to be diligent wherever we are.
If you're kind of that worker that's there but useless and everyone
knows that, man, this person doesn't like working, this person's lazy,
this person's just...
Hey, don't share the gospel.
Because they're gonna be very confused at what you're talking about.
Because it's funny how it doesn't matter if they're lost.
If they're saved, if they're this or that, everyone knows what work
ethics should look like.
They don't have to read Proverbs to know that we
ought to work hard in our life.
So when they see someone professing Christ as Lord, but yet they're
lazy and everything they do, that doesn't make sense.
Y'all women this morning.
How diligent are you in the church?
Do you come prepared and ready for whatever task is at hand?
Do you have the attitude of, well, just let someone else do it?
What if they don't?
Our guests still need greeting.
Our facility still needs to be secure.
Our children still need teaching.
Blessings and good things comes with diligence.
Proverbs 6, verse 6, go to the ant, 0 slugger,
observe her ways and be wise.
Proverbs 104, poor is he who works with a negligent
hand, but the hand of the diligent.
Look what it says, makes rich.
And we check our attitude.
He must be diligent in all that we do.
That's in our home.
That's in our workplaces.
That's in our church.
And say everywhere we are.
But that's not all.
Look at the next part.
Romans 1211, not slothful in business, fervent
in spirit serving the Lord.
We must be serving.
We are commanded to be fervent in spirit.
Now this is quite simple.
When you walk in diligence and zeal
for the things and people of God, this is going to
naturally turn into passion.
That word fervent literally means in the Greek to
show enthusiasm and have great fervor.
It gives the picture of a boiling pot of water over a fire.
We have to understand that when the work of the Spirit is evident
in the life of a believer, there is an active and
lively outcome.
How can you be spirit filled and live as a funny dud?
Let me just tell you something.
My pastor friends make fun of me because the
way I preach and move and do all these things.
Let me tell you something.
I'm excited about what I'm doing right now.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
This is not, you didn't force me to do this.
This is not out of coercion.
This is not a manipulation situation.
This is God saying, do this.
Yes, sir, and I'm excited to do it.
That's all there is to it.
Listen, people sit and I'm not trying to call out pastors,
but if the pastor can't get excited about his message, why should you?
But there's people right now in churches that they
live under these leaderships that are not, and I'm not saying you have to hoop and holler.
There are some powerful men of God that can stand right behind a pulpit.
Read a manuscript and people give their life to Christ and get right with God.
I'm not saying the personality.
I'm saying they better be excited and passionate and fervent about God's word.
And that's how we ought to be.
Listen, you know why I love VBS?
Because, man, that's something that God has given us, blessed us with.
Children coming in for a whole week and people come in.
Well, I'm here, preacher, just count me count me in.
Whoa, go home.
I mean think about it.
Hey, uh, preacher, this kid, he's he's asking questions about the Lord.
Praise God.
answer them.
Be excited about it.
Guys, listen, we get excited about every little thing.
I'll watch reels, and I'll doomsroll, man.
I will laugh and crack up and show everyone, hey, look at this.
It's so fun.
And we get so excited about TikTok and social media.
But when we open up the eternal, infallible, everlasting word
of God, all of a sudden we get this hush.
That's ridiculous.
Every time something good and new happens when God is doing a new work instead
of being excited and passionate, about being involved, it's
like some people bring ice water to the situation.
Something, listen, I know the church has their logistics.
I know the church has the policy and procedures, but sometimes, man, it's just good just to do.
Right, I've had people come to me and they say, hey, I want to get my life to Christ
and the church will say, well, ask them all these questions first.
And I understand that and I get what we're trying to do, but sometimes
you just need to lead someone to Christ and be excited about it.
This is a rotten attitude in church.
I think it's important to be decent and orderly.
I believe in keeping with a doctrine handing down all the way from the New Testament.
I believe that not every new thing is a good thing.
Trust me, I believe that.
But I can tell you one thing.
Jesus told us that we would do greater things.
John 14, starting verse 12.
Truly truly, I say to you, he who believes in me, the
works that I do, he will do also and greater works than these
he will do because I go to the Father.
Whatever you ask in my name, that will I do so the
Father may be glorified in the Son.
If you ask me anything in my name, I will do it.
We are also promised that God will use us in ways that we cannot even imagine.
Ephesians 3, in verse 20, now to him who is able to do far
more abundantly beyond all that we ask or think, according to
the power that works within us, to him be the glory, in the church,
and in Christ Jesus, to all generations forever and ever.
Amen.
Could it be that God is not doing these great things because we're not asking?
Because the Bible says he can do even better than we ask.
Even more than we ask, even greater.
Are we asking so small that God is just giving us what
we're asking instead of the abundance?
Do you see a theme here?
When God does a work in the lives of his people and brings a local church
to a level of ministry that is effective and impactful, that's
something to be excited and active about.
Listen, I believe that we love church.
I believe that Cedar Grove, the people here, I believe that we love to gather together.
But I'll never forget, when I 1st started preaching back in 2017,
18 and 19, man.
It was almost like there was there was a sense and a feeling
in the room every single Sunday.
Wow.
Because something like this had not happened for a long time.
There's been good ministry on this hill.
There's been this, but man, there was people flocking to this hill.
There were people giving their life to Christ.
The baptistry that was dried up was getting filled up.
I'm telling you right now, people was coming with an expectant attitude because
they knew God was going to work and they wanted to be a part of it and see it themselves.
I like that kind of church.
When this becomes a job, we're in trouble.
Are y'all with me?
Come on, be with me.
What kind of fervor do you have?
What gets you excited?
Some people have fervor about conflict and tension.
Ooh, would you hear what?
She hear what happened.
Let me tell you what happened.
Can I tell you, I should break our heart and not get as excited.
What gets you excited?
Tells a lot about you.
There's only one other instance of this particular term used here.
Talking about his ferventness deal.
is in Acts 18 when we introduced to a man named Apollos.
It's the only other time, this particular word is used.
It says this.
Now, a Jew named Apollos, an Alexandrian by birth,
an eloquent man came to Ephesus, and he was mighty in the scriptures.
This man had been instructed in the way of the Lord, and being fervent in spirit.
He was speaking and teaching accurately the things concerning Jesus,
being acquainted only with the baptism of John.
So he had a very he had a very small repertoire
of knowledge, but whatever he knew, man, he was excited about and
he was sharing with anyone he could.
And he began to speak out boldly in a synagogue, but when Priscilla and Aquila heard him,
They took him aside and explained to him the way of God more accurately.
And when he wanted to go across to Achaia, the brethren encouraged
him and wrote to the disciples to welcome him.
And when he arrived, he greatly helped those who had believed through
grace, for he powerfully refuted the Jews in public,
demonstrated by the scriptures that Jesus was the Christ.
And I'll tell you something, it's fun to do ministry with people that are excited about ministry.
that are fervent, passionate about the things of God.
This is a beautiful example of how of someone who is so passionate
about Jesus that even though he didn't know everything, he shared what he did know.
I've heard so many times, well, preacher, I can't go to door to door.
I can't go to outreach, or I can't do this.
I just don't know enough.
Well, listen, you better know Jesus lived down and rose again because you got to know that to be saved.
And so does everyone else who's lost.
So therefore, share what you know.
Guess what?
God can use that.
Church, you've heard me say it time and time again.
I don't know everything about God, but what I do know, I really, really like.
Apollo did not let ignorance or lack of education or training or even
opportunity keep him from sharing Jesus fervently.
As a matter of fact, everything that he learned from that point on, just made him
more fervent, more passionate, more bold.
I want to close today by finishing the verse, Romans 1211,
not lagging behind in diligence, fervent in spirit
serving the Lord.
We are commanded to be zealous for the Lord, diligent in our walk,
excited and active in our faith, and to be serving the Lord.
I want you to think of someone you would love to meet.
Just think of someone right now, you love to me.
don't be sunny school, okay?
Life groups that's not going on right now.
Just genuinely think someone that would be cool to meet.
Okay?
You don't have to tell because you might be embarrassed with if you told everybody.
I want to meet the rock.
you know, like someone like that, you know what I'm saying?
Just a celebrity singer, whatever it is.
Um, Singer, actor, business mogul,
athlete, team owner, whoever it is, let's say that person called you up.
And said I want you to work for me.
I want you to join my family.
I want you to get all the benefits that involves.
I want you to have access to me personally.
All the resources you could ever need to be successful.
They're yours.
A purpose in life that cannot be matched.
This is the dream job of a lifetime.
Whoever you had in your mind, let's say, hey, they're wanting
to hire you, they don't want just to meet you.
They want to have a relationship with you.
They want to provide for you.
They want to help you assist you.
Are y'all with me?
You know what we do?
And we jump up and down.
Oh my, we would we would thank this person over and over.
Thank you so much for this opportunity.
Thank you for this job.
Thank you for this provision.
We would accept immediately.
We tell everyone that we know about this person who has changed our life forever.
It'd be like if Adrian Rogers came back from the dead and
said, Jacob, I'd like you to be a pastor on staff at Bellevue.
I be like, It
can't happen because he's dead.
Don't be with Londe.
I here, Cedar Grove.
I'm just saying, that's what I'm talking about here.
Listen, hey, we would tell everybody.
We would be so excited about this opportunity.
See, the girl, were you keeping up?
Be devoted to one another umbrella love, give preference to one another in
honor, not lagging behind in diligence, fervent in spirit, serving...
The Lord.
Do we realize who we serve?
Think about that for a second.
We serve the chief cornerstone.
We serve the rock, the holy and righteous one.
We serve the morning star, the firstborn from the
dead, the alpha, and omega.
We serve the true vine.
We serve the way, the truth, and the life.
We serve the resurrection and the life.
We serve the good shepherd, the gate, the door,
the light of the world, the bread of life, the amen,
the author and finisher of our faith.
We serve the redeemer, the mediator, the advocate,
the high priest, the lamb of God.
We serve the Savior.
We serve the king of the Jews, the root of
David, the lion of the tribe of Judah, the
everlasting Father.
We serve the mighty God, wonderful counselor, prince
of peace, the image of the invisible God, the only begotten son.
We serve the Lord.
We serve Emmanuel.
We serve the word, the Son of Man, the Son of God, the Messiah,
the king of kings, and the Lord of Lords, listen, church.
We serve Jesus Christ.
We should be excited and passionate about that.
That should keep us going forever until he calls us home.
How dare we do so apathetically and stagnant?
Let's go back to that illustration I gave you.
Now let's talk Sunday school.
There's anyone I want to meet is Jesus.
Face to face one day.
But until then, I'm gonna serve them.
And until then, my passion is gonna lie with him.
What gets him excited will get me excited.
What pleases him ought to please me.
Where is your zeal?
Where is your fervor?
You're excited about something.
You're passionate.
God made us passionate people.
Introvert, extrovert, doesn't matter.
There's something that gets you passionate.
If it's not Christ, then who and what?
And if you're here, And
maybe your diligence is not,
Listen, maybe you're diligent everywhere else but the church, listen, I want you to understand something.
I believe in outside of these walls, ministry.
You go out, you proclaim the gospel, you lead people to Christ,
you bring them back to the family, and they'll be a part of us.
That's the model of the church.
But can I tell you something?
There are people right here right now.
that need to see somebody excited about Christ.
We talk all the time about worship and this and that and and
I've been talking so much with my friends that we
talk about, you know, the church of Christ, old school.
They don't use instruments and stuff.
And listen, I don't believe that's an issue of salvation.
I just believe that's something that we disagree on, right?
I say all the instruments.
you know, why?
Because God gave them a gift to play those instruments.
And I believe that gift was founded way back
when God gave the 1st musician, that gift.
It was for him.
But see, what we'll do is, hey, we'll get excited at the CMAs.
That person will come out.
Man, people will start screaming.
Man, he's my favorite singer.
She's my favorite singer.
Oh, this is my favorite song.
And man, we'll put our hands up.
We'll shout, we'll high 5 people.
We'll spill our popcorn everywhere.
And then all they're singing about is beer.
Sex.
Drugs.
Worldly stuff.
That's where our passion loss.
Y'all with me?
Can we come into the church?
And we hear the eternal God.
The one who literally saved you from hell.
The one who made you a new creation.
The one who did not leave you comfortless, but sent you the comforter
of the Holy Spirit, who leads and guides
and reminds you what you've been taught.
We hear about Jesus.
who loved us so much that God sent his only son.
We hear about Jesus going to Calvary, giving his life for hours.
Shedding his own blood.
Being beat and flogged and humiliated so that we
could be forgiven.
Crown of thorns pushed upon his brow.
Nails in his hands, nails in his feet.
He hung in humiliation between 2 criminals.
And we sing that that didn't just happen, but 3 days later, he rose again.
And he's alive today.
You know what we do?
Amen.
And listen.
I'm not asking everyone to start barking like a chicken and clucking like a dog.
What I am saying is, we ought to get passionate for Jesus.
If somebody wants to get me, listen, I love fantasy football, I love this.
I love basketball, I love all the things.
But if someone really wants to get me going, you know what they are, all they ought
to be, I have to say is Jesus Christ.
Let's talk about them.
What has he done for you?
Let me tell you what he's done for me.
When his bound eyes close over this place.